英文字幕(油管用户): jonas1015119, Matt Soren, Seijatachi
翻译，压制: Bolshevik0
校对: Aisaka1436, Uezaki
For decades, the exact science of waifus has been a mystery,
数十年以来 二次元老婆的精密科学一直以来都是个谜
as our collective understanding of these entities and the ways humans react to them
这是我们得出的结论 基于我们对这些实体的理解和我们对她们的反应
continue to baffle scientists to the modern day.
持续困惑着现代的科学家们
So today, I would like to present my findings to you - the board -
所以今天 我想通过这块白板给你们展示我的发现
in hopes that one day this research can be expanded on and completed.
希望有一天这个研究能得到进一步研究并被完成
注: 洛夫克拉夫特是克苏鲁文化的缔造者
As far as we can tell, Waifus are horrific Lovecraftian beings of unknown origin
大致来讲 二次元老婆是一种未知起源的洛夫克拉夫特恐怖存在
with the power to destroy entire species by inhibiting their desire to breed.
她们能通过抑制一个物种的繁衍欲望来消灭这个物种
While we have been able to prevent this so far with the human race,
当我们人类目前还能阻止这些发生的时候
as time has gone on, their attacks have only become more effective,
随着时间的推移 她们的攻击将会变得更加有效
and we get closer to the possibility of mass extinction every day.
每天都在增加大灭绝的可能性
The widely accepted root of the word 'waifu'
二次元老婆 这个词的公认根源
stems from the butchered Japanese pronunciation of the English word "wife",
来自日式英语对老婆 这个词的糟糕发音
which has become the adopted explanation by popular culture.
而这种解释已经被流行文化所接受
But recent studies have suggested that
但是最近的研究表明
the word actually comes from an abbreviation to the question,
这个词其实来自一个问题的缩写
"WAIFU? Why Am I Forever Unloved?" -
老婆？为什么我总是找不到女朋友？
as the entities themselves serve as an answer to that question.
而这些二次元老婆则是这个问题的解答
The exact appeal of waifus stem from their power to invoke a dormant gene
二次元老婆的确切吸引力来自一段休眠基因的唤醒
present in all humans known as the Protecc Gene.
在所有人类中都存在 叫做保护基因
Once invoked, the Protecc Gene raises strong primal instincts in an individual,
一旦唤醒 保护基因 将把个体的原始本能水平提到最高
granting a sense of temporary euphoria,
达到一种短暂的狂喜状态
bypassing the developed logical brain, which would usually rationalize to an individual
会使人的想法绕过了平时让人讲逻辑讲道理的发达大脑
that spending over $100 for a JPEG printout on a bag of feathers
让人购买一袋超过100刀的表面打印着JPEG格式图像的羽毛
might actually be a bad idea.
不得不说是一种糟糕的情况
Even though the effects of the Protecc Gene is normally seen in humans,
即使保护基因 的影响在人类当中很常见
it should be noted that animals also possess it,
应该指出的是动物同样拥有这种基因
with the most recent case of its effects being seen in penguins,
最近一个例子是能看见在企鹅身上的影响
proving that even animals are not immune to shit taste.
证明了就算是动物也无法抵御这种辣鸡纸片人审美
While there is high variance among individuals as to which waifu is most appealing to them,
根据不同的个体对二次元老婆的不同喜好 二次元老婆的种类可以说是非常地多
a peculiar event occurs when enough anime fans gather together, as a sort of hive mind begins to form,
但是当动漫迷聚集在一起时 一件奇怪的事情发生了 某种蜂群思维开始形成
abandoning all sense of individuality in order to collectively determine the most superior waifu in any given set.
失去了个人的判断力 只为了集体决定出一个最强的二次元老婆
This event is known as the Best Girl Ultimatum,
一般称这件事为最佳女孩对决
注: SALTS本来是Smiled A Little Then Stopped 的缩写 后来导致盐salt也引申为糟糕的意思
an event that causes enough sodium chloride to form to poison the surrounding area.
这种活动能产生大量的氯化钠来毒害周边环境
Newcomers can often be confused as to what exactly constitutes a Best Girl,
新人可能会搞不清楚什么才是最佳女孩
but once an individual spends enough time in the community,
但是当一个人在社区里花费了足够多的时间之后
they may be able to develop an additional sense; a kind of sixth sense
他们或许会得到一种新感觉 某种第六感
in which, on initial viewing of a new show,
这种第六感呢 指的是他们刚开始看新动画的时候
they can immediately detect who will be Best Girl.
就能立刻发现谁将是最佳女孩
This phenomenon is known as the Compounded Anime Neural Character Exposure Response,
这种症状被称为加重动画神经角色暴露反应
though it's more commonly referred to by its shortened form:
当然更广为人知的缩写为
有毒
注: 释义参见urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=cancer
While there is yet to be any proven hypothesis around what makes a Best Girl in any given situation,
尽管对于最佳女孩 的产生还没有任何证实过的假说可以解释
I would like to propose the following theory
我将提出以下理论
that can break down the overall effectiveness of any given waifu in a Best Girl race.
能消除最佳女孩 评选中的任何影响
Let's start with Personality - this can be broken down into two parts: the Depth Determiner, and Disposability.
我们从性格开始讲起 分为艰难决定 类和可替代 类
The Depth Determiner refers to the credibility of a certain waifu, and this is a slippery slope.
艰难决定 的那些人 倾向于确定且固定的二次元老婆 但这是个深坑
Waifus are meant to represent a certain ideology within a life-partner,
这种二次元老婆意味着一个确定且理想的一生伴侣
and in this sense, they can almost be seen as something similar to deities.
在这种情况下 祂们就和神差不多
○
吐槽: 小
圆
忽然中枪
In fact, some waifus themselves are deities.
事实上 有些老婆本身就是神
Because hey, if an all-seeing all-knowing omnipotent being exists that could take any form,
因为全视全知全能的东西如果有存在形式
why couldn't it be...
难道就不可以是
吐槽: 凉宫倒地
...a Tsundere high school girl in short skirts?
……一个短裙傲娇高中少女
Or as some experts in Waifuology have suggested, why shouldn't it be...
或者是某些二次元老婆研究专家所说的那样 为什么不这样呢……
*quieter* a Tsundere high school girl in short skirts?
轻声说 一个短裙傲娇高中少女
However, it is important that they remain believable but not too believable.
但是 重要的是这些理论看起来还不太可信
Too perfect, and the entity may come off as one-dimensional, boring, and flat.
在太过完美的情况下 二次元实体可能以无聊的扁平一维形式表现
But too believable and they might become too hu-
但是在太过真实的情况下 他们可能变得太r
*loud choking noise*
r巨大的智熄声
H-*chokes trying to speak*
ré智熄到无法说话
HU-*chokes trying to speak once more*
rén智熄着还要说一次
- human.
rén类化
Which brings us to our second criteria: disposability.
于是我们就讲到了第二个标准 可替代 类
There is an abundance of choice when it comes to waifu types,
讲到二次元老婆的种类 那实在是太多了
but while different personality types cater to different individuals,
虽然不同的性格是用来满足不同人的需求的
a large subset may be filed as a Disposable Waifu,
有一种却可以被归类成一次性老婆
in which a waifu may just feel like a reskinned version of another character.
在这种情况下 老婆不过是另一个角色的换肤版本
This is not to be confused with Trash Waifus,
这可不能和垃圾桶老婆 混淆
as that refers to waifus picked up by individuals who have forsaken their humanity;
这指的是那些被失去人性的人认领的老婆
at least a bit more so than the usual anime fan.
至少垃圾桶老婆比普通动漫迷还要多一些
The important thing is that if a waifu can be easily swapped out to any similar character from elsewhere
重要的是 如果二次元老婆可以被其他类似的东西轻易替换
without much overall impact in-universe, it increases their disposability.
如果替换后不会冲击整个动画世界观 这就增加了她们的可替代性
For example, if you replace Umaru with a piece of turd wearing an orange hoodie,
譬如 如果你把小埋用穿着仓鼠衫的屎进行替换
it would not actually make much of a difference to the in-universe narrative.
这并不会对这个动画的世界观和叙事造成很大影响
My apologies, I would like to make an amendment to that last statement.
对不起 我修正一下刚才的发言
It would actually make a massive difference.
确实会有很大改变
The piece of turd wouldn't be loud and annoying.
一坨屎不会那么吵
Physical characteristics are also a very important part of any waifu,
卖肉特征是二次元老婆的重要组成部分
吐槽: 我报警了 这里有个摄影师的手不受控制
我报警了 审核把这里和谐了
as any unique features may give them an advantage to others without them.
相比于不卖肉的角色 卖肉的老婆们可能具有更大的优势
This includes, but is not limited to:
包括但不限于
fangs, glasses, thigh-highs, elf ears, ponytails,
twin tails, real tails, big boobs, small boobs, no boobs,
虎牙 眼镜 丝袜 精灵耳
马尾 双马尾 真尾巴 大胸 贫乳 没胸
and of course, most powerful of all,
当然还有最有影响力的
a penis.
鸡儿
Sex appeal is also an important factor that is split into two sections.
性感的老婆也可以分成两部分
On one side, you have waifus with high sex appeal
一边是 人们会怀着赞美之心对待超性感老婆
that people very much appreciate and find totally acceptable to lewd.
同时觉得她们适合做那种事
And on the other side, you have the innocent kinds that have no sex appeal
而另一边是 你有那种完全不性感的天真无邪的孩子们
whatsoever that people just want to protect
但不管怎么样大家就想保护
and everyone agrees that under no circumstances are they acceptable to lewd.
所有人一致同意绝不应该对他们做那种事
But people lewd them anyway.
但还是做了.jpg
A waifu can increase their best girl chances by appealing to a certain fetish,
吸引恋物癖是一种能让二次元老婆成为最佳女孩的有力方法
but the real power comes when they allow an individual to discover a fetish they never knew they had.
但是真正的影响是 她们能让不是恋物癖的个体发现一些新的恋物癖好
However, sex appeal should never come at the cost of going against the ideology of being an ideal
可是 对于一个角色而言 因为性感元素只会增加婊子属性
注: THOT = That Hoe Over There
dedicated life partner, as this merely increases their Thot Factor,
所以如果性感元素加入过多 可能会违背理想人生伴侣的理念
which is a death sentence for any waifu.
等同于是给二次元老婆判了死刑
Then we get to arguably the most important factor for waifu's Best Girl candidacy:
接下来就到了最具争议最重要的最佳老婆 候选资格的部分
The Kawaii Coefficient.
可爱系数
This refers to unique attributes a waifu possesses which can be seen as 'cute'.
这是一种二次元老婆拥有的名为可爱 的属性
With a high-enough Kawaii Coefficient,
如果可爱系数 足够高
even seemingly one-dimensional waifus can have a higher standing than they arguably should.
就算是那些表面上的一维老婆也能突破争议 获得更高分数
A common way to achieve this is by giving them a weird quirk.
一个让老婆变得可爱的普遍方法是让他们有奇怪的癖好
Maybe they really like explosions, or licking people, or smelling people, or they're...
也许她们喜欢爆炸 舔人 闻人 又或者她们……
...mentally disabled, or they're a
石乐志 失了智
psychotic nut-job mass murderer,
精神失常的坚果杀手
or they're a mentally disabled psychotic nut-job mass murderer who's also
抑或是失了智的精神失常的坚果杀手
a Loli.
又同时是小女孩
Whatever it is, it should be noticed
不管是什么 需要注意的是
that pretty much any quirk can be turned into something cute within the Laws of Waifu,
在二次元老婆法则的影响下 任何怪癖都会变成某种可爱的东西
even if it makes absolutely no sense in the real world.
哪怕是现实世界中根本没意义的东西
If she's overly aggressive and borderline abusive,
如果她又好斗又好骂
we call that "being Tsundere".
我们把这叫做傲娇
If she's a wise wolf god wandering the world in human form, we call that
如果她是探索世界的人形智慧狼神
"Fuck you Dave, this is not Bestiality".
我们称这个为 Dave我可去你玛德 这不是人兽
And if she's a 500-year old immortal vampire who also happens to be trapped in a Loli body, we call that
如果她是500岁的永生吸血鬼 但也困在萝莉的身体里
"I swear Officer, she's totally legal".
我们把这叫做 警察叔叔我发誓这是合法的
The rules of the real world do not apply to waifus.
现实中的规则不适用于二次元老婆
吐槽: 根据拟兽理论的影响力 任何东西都可以成为老公 (furry并感)
In fact, through the power of anthropomorphism, anything can be a waifu.
事实上 根据拟人理论的影响力 任何东西都可以成为老婆
Anything
任何东西
Cats. Ships. Horses.
猫 船 马
Anything is fair game, so it's only really a matter of time before we see...
对待所有东西都该一视同仁
...anthropomorphized vacuum cleaners. *starts laughing*
出现拟人吸尘器只是时间问题 开始笑
Wait. Are you – ?
等一哈
– are you fuckin' – ??
你没开玩笑吧
注: Anthropomorphized Inanimate Object意思是尚未动画化的拟人化物体
简介里的描述是一个喜欢清洁的拟人化吸尘器 常常迷路 像个哭泣的婴儿
*in the distance* Are you FUCKING KIDDING ME?!?
一定距离下发出的声音 你耍我呢
注: 这里应该是META = Most Effective Tactic Available 是lol里面的主流套路的意思 上单中单什么的
Of course, this brings us to the most complex mechanic to understand, which is known as the Waifu Meta.
当然 这将引领我们去理解最复杂的机制 老婆套路
The cutthroat game of Best Girl is a constantly changing landscape,
最佳女孩 比赛竞争激烈 形势总在发生变化
with new additions continually being added
新作不断加入
which affect the overall ecosystem, changing the effectiveness of everything we previously talked about.
改变了整体的生态环境 改变了之前我们讨论的所有东西
An understanding of this landscape rapidly improves a waifu's standing in the current meta,
理解这种形势才能增加老婆在当前套路中的声望
and can increase or decrease their viability for best girl in any given situation.
或增强或削弱她们在任何情况下的生存能力
For instance, someone like Emilia was quite strong on release,
譬如说 爱蜜莉雅在刚出现的时候很强
having pretty solid base stats in every category that made her a popular pick.
在任何领域都拥有着坚实的数据 促使她成为大众之选
But pretty soon after, she just got completely hard-countered by Rem,
但是很快地 她就被雷姆完全打倒了
giving her a loss by default where she hasn't been able to recover ever since.
由于她没能采用行动 导致失败 甚至从那以后就没有恢复过来
Something similar happened recently between Zero Two and Ichigo from DARLING in the FRANXX,
同样的事情也发生在DitF中的02和莓身上
but that was more the result of a high tier waifu being called out for a 1v1
但这更像是高阶老婆被某人单挑
注: 青铜段位是最低的排位
by someone who is clearly still trying to climb out of bronze.
而这位还在青铜段位挣扎
The effects of the Waifu Meta are so severe that there have been time periods where
老婆们的套路影响实在是太厉害了
nonsensical pics such as Dio Brando and Kaiki have been viable for Best Girl,
有时候甚至迪奥·布兰度和贝木泥舟都有能力荒谬地参选最佳女孩
even if science has never even classified them as waifus.
即使科学意义上他们都不被分类为老婆
It is also able to counteract the importance of previously discussed factors.
这甚至能抵消之前所讨论的部分的重要性
Disposability is less of a factor if a waifu is the first to popularize a certain trend,
可替代性 不再是一个老婆带动流行趋势的重要因素
but a single imbalanced waifu is also able to start the revival of an old meta,
但是单方面突出的老婆也从以前的套路中复苏了
as we just saw last year with Sagiri bringing the resurgence of the Imouto Meta we hadn't seen since 2013,
正如去年我们看到和泉纱雾带动了妹妹套路 这是2013年以后不曾见到的
which absolutely nobody wanted but we ended up appreciating anyway.
绝对没人想要 但是不管怎样我们已经欣赏过了
Even someone as old as Asuka can remain relevant thanks to her constant reworks.
就算是老如明日香 也能因为不断的改编作品而保持热度
If this is confusing for you, then I recommend sticking to the comfort pics
如果这些数据让你困惑 我建议你直接坚持看这些舒服的图片
that have stood the test of time and have remained viable in almost every meta.
经过了时间的检验 在任何套路中都能生存下来
For example, someone like Rin will always remain a strong pick,
譬如说远坂凛总是有很强的竞争力
as she's in the Tsundere class, which will pretty much always be viable.
正因为她处在傲娇类型中 傲娇总是有很强的生存力
But this gives her very high synergy with her Twin Tail and Thigh-High builds,
但是傲娇属性和她的双马尾还有丝袜很搭配
plus having one of the best Blush skills in anime when fully maxed.
同时如果技能升满了 她还有动画里最强的脸红技能之一
The only thing she has going against her is when Saber is counter-picked,
有一点是克制她的 是当Saber在她的对面的时候
and even then it comes down to an even skill match-up.
哪怕是最均衡的匹配也会被克制
In conclusion, the science behind waifus and their ability to become Best Girl is a complicated field,
总的来说 老婆背后的科学和她们成为最佳女孩 的能力是一个复杂的领域
and science is still a ways away from being able to find the ultimate Best Girl.
而科学仍然未能发现最强女孩
While we can rationalize a lot of the power through
尽管我们能将许多影响力合理化
Depth Determiner, Disposability, Thot Factor, and the Kawaii Coefficient
譬如 艰难的决定 可替代性 婊子属性 可爱系数
through the power of the Waifu Meta and pretty much anything being able to be turned into a waifu
老婆主流套路和那些任何东西都能变成老婆的方法
- whether it be through anthropomorphization or just putting a blush effect on something -
不管是什么拟人理论还是往马桶上什么东西上加脸红效果
further research is required.
需要进一步研究
But from what we have discussed today, I can conclude only one thing for certain:
不过根据今天的讨论 我能总结出一个确切的东西
给动画迷一个物体
他们一定会找个方法去日它的
现在可以想想拟人化的吸尘器本子……
[Music]
悠闲的音乐
Hey guys, hope you enjoyed that video! Thank you very much this month to:
嘿 大家好 希望你们能看得愉快 感谢以下人士
and everyone else on Patreon for helping support me for this month and making this video possible.
以及任何其他这个月在patreon上支持我的人 没有你们无法做出这期视频
注: 这视频2018.05.19.发布的 所以这句话已经过时了
Not too many updates today, just repeating the fact that I will be at MCM London next weekend,
更新不是很多 只是重复一下我下周要去伦敦MCM
so if you're about on either the Friday or Saturday and see me walking around, feel free to come say hi!
所以如果你在周五或者周六能看到我 跟我打个招呼
Keep an eye out on my Twitter @GiggukAZ for any updates
注意我的推特 @GiggukAZ 的更新
and just in case I have enough time to sort out a small meet-up or something like that.
注意一下我也可能有时间搞个小型见面会
Anyway, that's it from me, I've been Gigguk, and I will see you all next time!
不管怎么说 今天先到这儿 下次再见